Now that we have an idea about how to identify hazards,
既然我们已经明白了如何对危害进行识别
we need to evaluate the risk associated with each hazard.
我们需要对每种危害的风险进行评估
Evaluating risk will be an important part of our more formal functional safety analysis.
在更为正式的功能安全分析中 风险评估会是及其重要的一部分
Every hazard has a certain risk associated with it.
每种危害都会对应若干种风险
And since we are thinking like functional safety engineers,
既然我们是从功能安全工程师的角度进行思考
we are going to define risk numerically.
我们就以数值的方式来定义风险
Risk equals severity of harm times probability of occurrence.
风险可以用其严重程度和其发生概率的乘积定义
Severity of harm measures how badly a person could be injured when an accident occurs.
严重程度用来衡量在事故中一个人可能受到伤害的严重程度
Probability of occurrence has a specific definition for passenger car functional safety.
在客用汽车的功能安全中 发生概率有一个特定的定义
It is the frequency with which
它是指驾驶员在某种特定的驾驶
typical drivers find themselves driving in a certain situation.
环境中进行驾驶的频率
For example, driving on a city street has
比如 在城市的街道上驾驶时风险的发生概率
a high probability of occurrence because people do it everyday.
比较大 因为人们每天都会在这种路况下行车
Driving on a snowy mountainside has
在积雪的山地中行车有则有着
a low probability because people hardly find themselves driving in those conditions.
较低的发生概率 因为很少有人会在这种路况下行车
Probability of occurrence only takes into
发生概率仅仅考虑
account how often you find yourself driving in a certain situation.
你在某种特定的驾驶环境中驾车的概率
It does not take into account how likely a malfunction will occur,
它并不考虑某一功能失灵可能性的大小
like the probability of your brakes failing.
例如在你行车过程中刹车失灵的可能性
Failing brakes would lead to
刹车失灵有着
high severity but would not affect probability of occurrence.
很强的严重程度 但是它并不影响发生概率
Let's go through an example of calculating risk.
让我们学习一个评估风险的例子
We'll say that severity has a scale of one to four,
我们将严重程度的范围定义为1到4之间
with one representing no injury and four representing fatal injury.
1表示没有伤害 4表示致命的伤害
Probability of occurrence will also be on a scale from one to four,
发生概率的范围也定义为1到4
one being an unlikely scenario like needing a jump start,
1代表不太可能发生的情况比如汽车需要跨接启动
while four will be a likely scenario like driving on a highway.
而4则代表经常出现的情况 比如在高速公路上行驶
Here's our scenario, you're driving on
下面是我们模拟的情景 你行驶在 00:01:45,739 --&gt; 00:01:49,655. 充满积雪的山路边缘并且你的车的动力转向系统失灵
I would say severity is a four because we could easily lose control of the vehicle,
我可以认为严重程度是4因为这辆车会轻易的失控
driving off the mountainside and suffer a fatal injury.
坠下山崖并造成致命的伤害
Probability of occurrence could be a two
发生概率可以定义为2
because you would not find yourself driving on a snowy mountainside very often.
因为你很少会在积雪的山路上行驶
Risk then is four times two equals eight.
风险的数值就等于4乘以2等于8
In functional safety analysis,
在功能安全分析中
we quantify risk to determine how much we need to lower the risk.
我们将风险量化从而确定我们需要在多大程度上降低风险
Vehicle systems with high risks require
拥有更高风险的汽车内部系统
more analysis and testing to bring the risk down to acceptable levels.
需要更多的分析和测试从而将风险降低至可以接受的范围之内